Guide to the Maurice F. Neufeld Collections 1903-1998
Neufeld, Maurice F., Collections
Kheel Center for Labor-Management Documentation and Archives, Cornell University Library
Maurice F. Neufeld Collections, 1903-1998
/4340
Neufeld, Maurice F.; Kheel Center for Labor-Management Documentation and Archives; McKelvey, Jean T.
137.5 linear ft.
non-fiction, clippings (information artifacts), scrapbooks.
Kheel Center for Labor-Management Documentation and Archives, Cornell University Library
Clippings from the New York Times, collected by Maurice F. Neufeld.
BIOGRAPHICAL NOTE
Professor Maurice Frank Neufeld (October 27, 1910 -April 10, 2003) was an American academic, author, union organizer and Army officer. In 1945, he was one of the two founding faculty members of the School of Industrial and Labor Relations at Cornell University, appointed by its founding dean, Irving Ives.
SUBJECTS
Names:
McKelvey, Jean T.(Jean Trepp), 1908-1998; Neufeld, Maurice F.; New York State School of Industrial and Labor Relations.
Subjects:
Labor movement -- United States.; Labor unions -- United States. 655: Records (documents)
Form and Genre Terms:
non-fiction.; Clippings (information artifacts); Scrapbooks
INFORMATION FOR USERS
Access Restrictions:
Access to the collections in the Kheel Center is restricted. Please contact a reference archivist for access to these materials.
RELATED MATERIALS
Related Collections:
5885: New York Times Additional Clipping File
/3001: Jean T. McKelvey Papers
/4165 OHT: Jean T. McKelvey Interview with Ronald Schatz
/4202: Jean T. McKelvey Additional Files
5154: New York City Office of Collective Bargaining Records
CONTAINER LIST
- /3007: Maurice Neufeld Papers, 1903-1994 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  62 linear feet.
- /3007 AV: Maurice Neufeld "Grass Roots Founders and Grass Root Prodders: The Sources of Venture and Renewal for Democratic Education" Speech Audio-Visual Materials, 1972 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  1 tape cassette and one 7" open-reel tape
- /4097: Maurice F. Neufeld "ILR History" Scrapbook, 1945-1970 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  1 linear foot
- /4131m: Maurice Neufeld Additional Papers, 1938-1992 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  1 file folder.
- /4208: Maurice F. Neufeld and Jean T. McKelvey, eds. "Industrial Relations at the Dawn of the New Millennium" Monograph (Box 1, Folder 5)
  1 linear feet
- /4229: Maurice Neufeld Additional Files, 1944-1998 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  9 linear feet.
- /4229 AV: Maurice Neufeld "The Future of the American Labor Movement" Audio-Visual Materials, 1953 (Box 1, Folder 7)
  0.5 linear feet.
- /4230: Maurice Neufeld Additional Files (Box 1, Folder 8)
  23 linear feet.
- 5515: Maurice F. Neufeld Collection of New York Times Clippings, 1929- 1978 (Box 1, Folder 9)
  27 linear feet. Clippings from the New York Times, collected by Maurice F. Neufeld.
- 5777: Maurice Neufeld Documents and Clipping Files, 1946-1987 (Box 1, Folder 10)
  14 linear feet.